[Music]
excellent John it's great to have you
back sir good to be back thanks for the
invitation of course of course the last
time we sat down at the end of October
we got a lot of your story probably not
the full thing that's not really
possible even in six and a half hours or
whatever the we did but you know I
talked with you obviously I've enjoyed
your podcast with Danny over the years
where you're breaking down the
geopolitics of things and I hope to see
you do that with Dalton as well moving
forward but you know there's a lot going
on right now there's a lot and I'm I'm
like a little bit I'm a little bit at
fault here because last time when we
were about five hours in you started
telling this story and you're like I'll
give you an example Afghanistan 2009
poppy everywhere everywhere and I'm just
sitting there like wow okay little did I
know you were blowing the whistle on the
whole USA thing before this was like
cool to do that I guess I guess I was
congratulations on that so for for
everyone out there who's hearing about
USA they've seen Mike mercedesbenz on
all these podcasts and stuff talking
about it he's been blowing the whistle
on it obviously elon's working on it
we'll get to that you know what what
what was it to you when you were in the
CIA how did you view USA and what kinds
of things were they doing back then and
then we'll work to today to tell you the
truth when I was in the CIA still I paid
very very little attention to uh to USA
ID I didn't have any U interaction with
them every once in a while you'd bump
into them in you know an embassy that
you happen to be working in or most of
the big embassies have a bar you can go
to after work and you'd see them having
drinks over there but I you know I never
had to interact with them so with that
said I I was aware that
usaid um was giving money to the
National Endowment for democracy and
there were accusations that that was a
CIA front organization it wasn't a
legitimate Think Tank and you know
there's a lot of what you and I might
call L money money laundering going on
uh others would say you know were were
private uh Public
Partnerships uh but now it's all coming
out in Afghanistan in ' 09 I wasn't
working for the CI anymore I was working
for the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee and I was under the staken
belief that I was uh I was free to
investigate what I want what I wanted
and to you know make that information
public and in retrospect I wasn't would
you just for people out there who didn't
see episode 250 that was the second one
we did you told that story maybe a
couple hours in can you just run through
what you found there and then how it was
shut down just to review it sure um I
was keenly aware that Afghanistan at the
time was producing 93% % of the world's
so as recently as the 1970s Afghanistan
was a net food exporter there's not very
much land there that's arable there's
not very much water but the the arable
land that they have they made very good
use of and they could feed themselves
and Export rice to Pakistan and Iran so
that's that's pretty good yeah for a
country that's you know 90% mountains
yep well um
after the Taliban were overthrown they
converted all their food production to
Opium
poppy because it's profitable right and
as a result by 2009 after eight years of
you know
American control or occupation or
whatever your politics want you to want
you to call it uh they accounted for 93%
of the world's heroin so I wanted to go
to Afghanistan and I wanted to
investigate this I was the senior
investigator on the Senate Relations
Committee working for John krey at the
time your favorite guy yeah my favorite
guy we can we yeah there's a lot to say
about John
krey so I'm so grossly disappointed in
John Carrey yeah so
um so I I got the um concurrence uh of
the American Embassy in Cabell I flew
out to Afghanistan and I went to B Bas
and I had trouble
immediately I said that I wanted to go
to kahar Province and Helman province in
the South that was the center of of
poppy
cultivation and um and they didn't want
to fly
me and I did something that I never ever
do I pulled Rank and I said listen I'm a
senior staffer of the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee I have the rank of
brigadier general I'm not asking you to
fly me I'm telling you we're going to
fly down there what was the
reaction somebody start up the
chopper I've I had never done that
before in fact once I went to
Afghanistan and we were on a 16 seat uh
military plane U going to Dubai to catch
a commercial flight back to DC um and it
was a whole bunch of generals and a
handful of us staffers and uh 16 seats
on the plane there were 17 of us and so
this this General says oh I'll I'll stay
behind another day I go absolutely not
I'm not going to be responsible for a
general not making it home after
finishing his his tour in Afghanistan he
said no no you outrank me I said
absolutely not and so I stayed another
day in in Cabell so he could go home to
his family but anyway that that took me
off the subject so I I go to to kahar we
meet with a handful of people there and
then we fly to lashara which is a a
village in the center of Helman province
there was something called a PRT there
uh that was a state department um
provisional reconstruction team is what
it stood for a state department
organization it also had military and
had usaid and a couple of other uh
organizations that were represented
there but they were doing things like
trying to build a a a um an electrical
Grid or digging water wells stuff like
that so positive things yeah yeah yeah
legit things so um we got off the
helicopter and the state department
people greet us and and I said I want to
I want to just drive out into the poppy
fields now when you're coming in to
lashara as far as the eye can see it's
just poppy MH and I mean for miles and
miles and you can see these Rivers
running through the province and they're
diverting water from the rivers just to
cultivate the poppy who is doing that
well see that's that's an important
question for the most part it's
just itinerant Farmers dirt
farmers um and they're
being in some cases told what to grow
and that became an issue for me so I
said listen we're going to drive out
into the poppy fields the military
escort that I had said absolutely not
and I said no we absolutely are going to
drive into the poppy fields because I
have questions to ask right I'm not
doing this for vacation yeah you know I
didn't want to go to Afghanistan
this was because the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee members had a
legitimate interest in you have a job to
do I had a job to do so we get in this
Jeep two Jeeps uh security was in one
Jeep and it was me and a driver and a
state department guy translator uh in
the other Jeep we go out to the into the
fields we find a poppy farmer so I asked
him this very naive question and I said
why do you grow poppy when instead you
could be growing things with two growing
Seasons like Tomatoes or onions or
pomegranates he he was very frustrated
he goes
H the Americans told me in 2001 if I
told them where the Arabs were I could
grow all the poppy I wanted and I said
what Americans told you you could grow
poppy as soon as I said it the military
guys were like meeting over and they
pull me back into the Jeep we're under
threat there was nobody out there but
we go back to the base so I I fly back a
couple of days later and I I called one
of my contacts at DEA and I said I got
to write this paper but I want to talk
to you first because I saw some stuff
that that's just not right yeah so
they've got this secret facility out in
the sticks in Virginia I drive out there
and I I told them everything I had seen
and
um and the one guy says to me you're
never going to get this paper published
and I said why not it's all first person
it's I saw it with my own eyes plus I
interviewed you know DEA and a whole
bunch of different people that that
could be quoted so he said you don't get
it yeah it's 93% of the world's poppy
but it all goes to Russia and Iran and
we want them to be addicted to it
weakens their societies it weakens their
cultures we want them to be addicted to
drugs can I ask a really really
difficult question here that sucks to
ask
sure I think that's horrible it's awful
it's awful
yeah trying to play Devil's Advocate
with the emphasis on
Devils it's being done to us like crazy
with fentel absolutely so could you not
to excuse it or Say in any way they
should do it but could you see where the
reactionary human emotion comes from in
the decision makers where it's not just
necess not just necessarily like let's
be evil they're more like them they're
doing it t we're going to do it to them
without a doubt and that's why this
Lefty supports Donald Trump's decision
to send troops to the border and to
crack down on China yeah yeah because
they do it to us yep MH so that's the
better way yeah to deal with this stuff
is to use your resources to stop stop it
and not have to do it to someone else
cuz you're also spending you're
funneling taxpayer money through poppy
fields yeah poppy fields and you know
the funny thing too is you you look at
these charts that are produced by DEA
and it's it's the amount of poppy
produced in Afghanistan over the last
like 40 years the years that the Taliban
were in charge they produced almost no
Poppy and then in 200
one they didn't produce any poppy at all
they were terrible businessmen that's
the problem it's just it's a business
thing John we're good at that here we
bring New York City out there we bring
our public companies we know how to
spend money they don't know how to do
that I'll tell you another thing that
they're not very good at uh when I was
out there uh one of the one of the
military guys that I was working with
showed me a satellite photo of
Afghanistan of Southern Afghanistan
taken at night okay so so it was it was
measuring heat heat production and there
were these little pin Pricks of light
all over Southern Afghanistan I said
what is that they can't be Villages
they're too small and he said um they're
processors MH yeah that's what it is
every little house every little mud hut
or Shack that's out there in the fields
at night you're not going to farm at
night so at night you cook the
poppy
how strongly connected is this Sinister
Bond it's obviously strongly connected
but let me paint a picture for you to
tell you how I'm thinking about it I'm
just thinking Hollywood right now MH
okay you know in the movies when there's
like the evil warehouse and Productions
happening you see all these people and
let's even make it stereotypical here
they're speaking some foreign language
and they're making drugs and give people
whatever it might be and the camera's
panning cross you're meeting all the
characters in there the manager talks to
this guy whatever eventually he goes to
his office when he gets into his office
there's a shadowy figure sitting in a
chair with a M envelope that's yay thick
and they hand it to him speaking you
know yeah The King's English if you will
the president's English I should say in
American and they say keep it going is
it literally like that or is it more
we're going to let this happen yeah the
latter okay yeah it's not so
sophisticated yeah yeah there were other
issues too that I I really struggled
with I I don't remember if we talked
about the dash Deele Massacre last time
I was here I believe it came up fil me
in on what it was again this was
something that was actually pretty
important to me during my time at the
Senate Foreign Relations Committee on
November 30th and December 1st 2001 mhm
2,000 Taliban soldiers yes gave up on
Moss we did talk about yeah in the
northern L please please review this
yeah well there there was no were to put
2,000 people all at once there's no
prison in Afghanistan that can hold
2,000 people so we told the Northern
Alliance which at the time was led by
General abdar rashed doam one of the
most genocidal violators of human rights
in the last century um he was in charge
of the Northern Alliance we these guys
gave themselves up to the Northern
Alliance and he called us and said what
do I do with them and we said take them
out to the desert and hold them there
until we can divide them up into smaller
groups and then send them to jails and
prisons around the country to hold them
so they loaded these guys I don't
remember if it was four containers or
six containers whatever it was 2,000
guys they pack them into shipping
containers and put them on trucks on 18
wheelers and truck them out into the
desert but the thing is there were no
air holes and there was no water and
there was no food and of the 2016
survived yeah and one of the Survivor
said when they arrived in the desert and
they opened up the trucks the bodies
fell out like sardines from a can so in
the in the 2008 election Barack Obama
said that he was aware of this dhele
massacre and it had never been
appropriately studied and he was going
to get to the bottom of it that if he
were to win the presidency he was going
to task the National Security Council
with doing a study and figuring out who
was responsible for this
okay great that's exactly what I wanted
to hear so I told Carrie I said look you
know Obama made this uh statement and I
want to I want to take a look at it I'm
going to fly out to Afghanistan and and
um and investigate before I did that
though I got a call from a human rights
activist and not one of these you know
Looney ones you know like a serious
human rights activist from a serious
important Human Rights group and so
um he said that he needed to tell me
something but it was too sensitive for
him to come up to Capitol Hill could I
meet him um I ended up meeting him in a
in a darkened classroom at John's
Hopkins University so he said look I
have a I have a witness to the dashy L
Massacre who just came
forward and um this kid was 12 at the
time of the massacre now he was you know
what 21 MH and what was new that he
wanted to tell us was that when they
were opening up the
trucks he was hiding behind a rock and
he saw the bodies falling out of the
trucks but there were two men there
wearing blue jeans and black t-shirts
and speaking English yeah the CIA always
denied that there was any CIA presence
there well who in the world is going to
be in Dashi L
Afghanistan on December the 2nd 2001 but
the the CIA yeah nobody no other
Westerner from anywhere in the world is
going to be at that spot on December the
2nd so um I wrote a letter to the CIA
and we got Carri to sign it and I asked
for clarification I said we've developed
this information it appears to be
new were these CIA officers onsite at
the uh we called it the Box
up so six weeks passed
and
um a colleague of mine comes into the
office and he said hey the agency sent a
a response to your letter and I said I
didn't see any response I just checked
my mail an hour ago and he said oh they
classified it top secret it's it's down
in the vault well I only had a secret
clearance at the time so I said well
what did it say and he says it said go
yourself yeah and I said okay that's how
they want to play it all right so I went
to Carrie and I told him and he's like
yeah you're not publishing this thing
they've already called you're not
publishing I feel like this is the Trap
we run into all the time and it's the
thing I wrestle with the most about any
of these powerful agencies that are
under the Spy designation you will have
people there who work on tasks that are
vital to National Security and it's not
just a tagline it actually is real and
they do an ni shop maybe they stop a
terrorist attack things like that right
you then also have some people who
either through evil or through very very
radicalized group think get carried away
which are things that you were trying to
point out that you discovered while you
were still there and we know that whole
story but you'll have those people and
they'll do things that are very bad very
bad just like you're talking about right
now the argument that always gives them
cover to keep doing it is also the
argument that gives them cover to not
release it which is if you bring it to
the public the public is going to say
you look at this in this case I'll just
say it like this maybe this anecdotal
thing we know there's more problems than
that sure but they're going to say
that's anecdotal you're right you're
right it added to the body of evidence
but it was anecdotal but they're going
to then say shut it all down that's
right and now you have a problem because
then the good things that may also
happen here which a lot of people don't
want to hear and you know when you hear
about MK Ultra and stuff like that it's
it's kind of hard to say that but there
are some good things that happen it's
like then that baby goes out with the
bath water how do we fix that you're
exactly right you know really the only
way to fix it is through is through
transparency real transparency and true
Congressional oversight which we have
not had in decades in decades you
mentioned MK Ultra a moment ago MK Ultra
was a real thing most of the documents
were destroyed that's right by uh
director Helms in violation of the law
right um but even with all the documents
destroyed we still have a pretty darn
good idea of what Mk Ultra was and
pretty much every facet of it was
illegal yeah it was it was extensive
experimentation on American citizens
without their knowledge and without
their consent to the point where um
under something called MK chick Wht
which was a a subset of MK Ultra the CIA
actually weaponized a virus that they
that they blew into the San Francisco
fog just to see if people would get sick
and this was in the late 1950s and 11
people came down with this rare urinary
tract infection the doctors had never
seen before and so that was a success
that made them success oh yeah we can
weaponize this and you know maybe we we
blow this in Shanghai Harbor or in
Moscow in the summertime
uh another thing that they did also part
of MK Ultra is they recruited
prostitutes in San Francisco yes to go
out and find Jon's and bring them back
to what was really a CIA safe house it
was made to look like a cat house a CIA
Safe House drug them Y and then try to
get them to tell their innermost secrets
so they dosed them with LSD and with a
couple of other there were like six
different medications this was like
Sydney got Le's experiment right exactly
yeah it came from Sydney got's
experiment and uh you know is it's it
was supposed to be some sort of truth
serum right but with LSD as a base does
it work well who cares if it works these
guys never consented to be drugged by
you guys to tell their innermost secrets
and then you just dump them on the
street somewhere in San Francisco yeah
but that kind of thing was happening a
lot until 1975 Church commission the
church committee and the pike committee
and the house and they were appalled by
that and it it the church committee and
the pike committee morphed into the
Senate select committee on intelligence
and the house permanent select committee
on intelligence great and they had real
true legit oversight until about
um Bill Casey was Ronald Reagan's CIA
director case great guy oh lovely lovely
man yeah he's a real looker too and a he
must have done well with the see he was
years ahead with the giant lips thing
that he had going
on so he was he's a former OSS officer
office of strategic Services which was
the cia's predecessor
organization and just a True Believer
and he did his darnest to cut Congress
out of everything and then that ended up
giving us you know Iran Contra and all
kinds of different terrible scandals he
ended up dying of a of a way at a stroke
in the he had an aneurysm a brain
aneurism um so died just before the end
of his term um but by then the oversight
committees really didn't have any idea
what the CIA was doing and so they went
so far as to have a vote in 1986 it was
a no confidence vote in Casey as the
DCI
and the way they ended up getting it
passed in a negotiation with the
Republicans was
was it's it sounds so stupid now in
retrospect but they they voted to say
that William Casey is not unqualified to
continue as
director
meaning I see what they're doing so
they're basically just trying to like
put a little in there but politic it to
say but he still can yeah we're not
asking that he resign yeah but we're
saying that he's he's not doing great
yeah he's not doing great that's right
that's right uh but ever since then I
mean there's not been any real oversight
when the Democrats on the Senate
intelligence committee did the Senate
torture report uh what a decade a little
bit more than a decade ago that report
as it was published was Democratic staff
only there were no Republicans involved
no Republican staff and no Republican
members it was a democratic uh
product excuse me and then the
Republicans came out with with a the
counter to it that they published and
what was that oh we love torture and it
wasn't torture it was it literally said
that yeah it worked it was it was moral
it was right it's like okay if that's
what you're going with you know don't
let me stop you yeah so the the other
problem though if when you look at the
history of you bring up the the church
committee that guy Frank Church who it's
named after yep I believe the committee
commen in 74 or 75 correct something
like that yep so he won his senate
election in 74 he he won he won
re-election in 74 because Richard Nixon
had just um had just resigned and it was
the worst most devastating that's right
kill job in the 20th century that's
right yeah point being though his next
election was six years later and he got
crushed and he got crushed yeah and it's
cuz there's some weird money that went
into the race against him we know where
that's coming from are exactly right you
know Frank church was one of those
giants of the 20th century I can I can
honestly tell you such Senators don't
exist anymore maybe though there will be
some someday but giants like who had a
place in American history we had a half
a dozen of them back then from both
parties but anymore they're just a bunch
of they're bought bunch of bozos yeah
yeah but this guy tries to make that
committee so that there can be oversight
or whatever and then the very people
that they're investigating I mean it
hearkens back to the old New York Times
headline where it's like the CIA
investigated itself on whether or not it
sold crack in the hoods and it found no
wrongdoing exactly that's what they're
doing here when the people who are
supposed to be pushing for the oversight
they can then use surreptitious ways
right to get them out of office and then
poof you never really hear about it
again because to your point there hasn't
been there have been arguments over like
the torture time or whatever but there
hasn't been some sort of like hand hands
on major oversight
commission since then yeah I was a
little kid when that was happening and I
remember my dad voting for Frank church
for president in the 1976 primaries my
mom had voted for Birch by from Indiana
I remember that I don't know why she did
but um my dad voted for for church and
my mom said really church and I remember
my dad saying that guy earned it if
anybody's ear earned it it was him mhm A
young John kirak that went in one year
not the other
apparently so joined up joined up with
the dark side right the dark
side well the context of all this and
what we're talking about and I
appreciate you running through some of
that again just so people can hear it
because you saw this hands on but the
context has to do with an organization
like USA and how it may be used for
terms of soft power now we pulled up a
link right here just for people to
review I know you and I were talking
about this a little earlier before we
got on camera lesie can you scroll down
a little bit these are are just some
highlights if you will y of different
things that have been uncovered since
they started investigating this so you
have 14 million in cash vouchers for
migrants at the southern border through
the state department you have
$20,600 for a drag show in Ecuador
through the state department you have
$7,777
the money on this sheet to you and me
it's a lot of money to what the actual
budget is it's a very small percentage
of it but like when I see things the
carelessness of like $10,000 to pressure
Lithuanian corporations to promote Dei
values through the state department John
do you know what $10,000 buys you yeah
nothing I can get like an editor in
Venezuela for that that's it all right
like that's I think you said it you you
put it best you're like that could buy
you two Facebook ads yeah that's it and
that and they characterize it as
pressure now to you and me $10,000 very
small part of the budget here but that's
a lot of money to me it's like if
they're this careless with that
$10,000 how many other things are they
this careless with and what does any of
the stuff you're seeing here which
frankly a lot of the highlights that
they've decided to pick out because it
is and I'll be fair like it is a
republican who's pointing these things
out they're picking out the LGBT stuff
and the Dei stuff because that's like
the you know soup theour right now but
like when you add up probably all the
things that are in that type of Lane
like something that seems totally
unnecessary it probably adds up to a lot
and is something where we've lost the
oversight completely in the
organization MH you're exactly right you
know two years ago I was I was one of
six um independent journalists who were
invited to have lunch with the Russian
ambassador to the United States
and we we went to the to the residents
it was this big formal deal so it was
the Ambassador the deputy Ambassador and
like three of his staff members and six
of us journalists and he had read
um articles that all of us had written
he actually quoted them which really
struck me and the reason for the lunch
was for the most part he wanted our
ideas on how the US and Russia could
cooperate in a time of war and I gave my
standard thing counterterrorism counter
proliferation counternarcotics
um but the thing that made him
angriest was how the state department
pushes lgbtq
on countries where it is culturally
unacceptable and he said you know we
don't even mind being adversaries on
some of these issues our interests are
different sometimes from American
interests he said you're right we can
cooperate on counter terrorism we can
cooperate on on counter proliferation
that's a great idea no problem but don't
force us to accept trans people in our
government Don't Force us to to accept
lgbtq people in positions of authority
in the Orthodox church we will not do it
you don't respect our culture and he
said that's a bigger problem than not
respecting our
policies why do they do it because like
I I like living in a country where
people are are are free to be themselves
and do what they want to do that's a
beautiful part of America Agreed 100%
it's different when you're pushing like
I would in In fairness like my gay
friends like this is not this is push
like some sort of business commissioned
ideology on places to make them probably
pay more attention to it in a negative
light than they would have in the first
place if you didn't do it exactly
exactly so why do they do it people some
of the people who might be impacted by
like8
$8,000 to promote Dei among lgbtq groups
in Cyprus
well everybody in Cyprus is Greek
Orthodox right the Orthodox Church of
Cyprus
there is no such thing as
lgbtq in a in a culture like that it's a
conservative culture it's offensive I I
recognize that it's only $8,000 and I'm
glad 8000 that we that we have it here
I'm glad I welcome it I celebrate it
truly but we we shouldn't be imposing
our own values our own cultural values
on countries that don't want it yeah I
don't I it just it's seems so especially
when you look at like I was saying the
amounts it's not doing anything no so
when you look at like the The Devil's
Advocate to like us Aid and we can talk
about this because I think you'll
probably have a lot of thoughts here is
that it has to do with this idea of soft
power and we already mentioned the
extreme example of like pushing drugs
into other countries earlier but where
there are countries like I don't know
China Russia ran who are running around
and maybe building roads in places to
Curry favor oh I'm so glad you brought
that up or give debt you know basically
create debts and say don't worry about
it but now we get to do this with you I
understand why the United States would
want to have things like that I just
don't want to see it have stupid [__]
like this and I don't want to see it not
have oversight does that make sense
you're right and then that leads to the
question of why is it that the Chinese
are building ports and Roads and
hospitals and airports all over the
world and we're doing that right what do
we have to show for that we have nothing
nothing it's like democracy in
Afghanistan this has long been a big
deal for me why in blazes did we force
Afghanistan into a western style
democracy when in the 3,000 years of
that country's history they never had a
western style democracy they had this
system called the Loya jurga which
worked a
it's a consultative council of tribal
Chieftains and so if you and I are in a
dispute I I say that my land ends here
and you say no it ends here and we have
a conflict with one another we go to the
lawyer jurga and they we each give our
side and they settle the dispute or um I
want to be the village you know tax
collector let's say we go to the loyal
jurga I make my pitch the other guy
makes his pitch the loyal jur of votes H
they choose you know this guy oligarchs
instead of Kings yeah right right so we
said no no we we recognize you guys have
been doing that for thousands of years
but we don't like that instead we're
going to have uh an election and we got
this guy Hamed
carai and his brother's got a nice
restaurant in Baltimore you can you can
have lunch at his Afghan restaurant
Baltimore is very popular and so that
real uhhuh it really did uhhuh in
Baltimore yeah there's like six good
blocks in Baltimore I know that's about
it and and they still call it Greek
Town yeah and
uh and they're like we don't uh we don't
want that kind of system and we said
yeah we're we're not asking you we're
telling you but then you know we're not
pushing democracy on Saudi
Arabia or on Kuwait or bahin or or even
Egypt which actually had a democracy for
a minute but when the wrong guy got
elected then
we said no a coup would be okay just
about
now why why did we CH Saudi Arabia I
think is more self-explanatory yeah but
like Egypt why do we decide that's okay
there but not in Afghanistan because the
Egyptian
populace um has an intense dislike of
Israel which is in opposition to our
foreign policy and there are so many
poor people we're afraid of a broad
uprising there they'll throw us out you
know it's it's going to be chaos what's
different about Afghanistan though cuz
there's a lot of poor people there as
well is it the geography more than
anything they thought they could get
away with it in part it's geography and
in part it's population there aren't
that many people in Afghanistan we
thought we can we can push these people
around and uh we can supply them with
whatever they need we have bases in
usbekistan Tajikistan we had the Drone
base in uh in in Pakistan that nobody
knew about
until until a a really smart thinking
reporter filed a Freedom of Information
Act request for all drone fuel
deliveries in
Pakistan and they're like oh sure here
you go all the someone got fired for
that like what's the Harmon asking where
all the fuel is coming from or where
where the fuel's going it's going right
here to this base oh wait a minute
that's a secret base oh sorry oh man
yeah but we just pushed them around yeah
and it didn't work I I say often too
that that the Taliban did not descend
from the Moon right and just they didn't
softly land in Afghanistan and take over
these are the the husbands the fathers
the brothers of Afghan women they they
Afghan families this is who they chose
to be led by they had 20 years of
American leadership they didn't like it
and so they chose the Taliban well we
didn't lead that's the other problem we
put in figureheads we tried to push as
you just laid out beautifully democracy
on a on a country where that wasn't
necessarily what they wanted or what
their history wanted and then we also
got oh I don't know Tangled Up in a
[__] war in Iraq so we pulled
resources that's right and there was all
kinds of [__] that that went on that led
to that steep Decline and it's not even
like the whole population supports the
Taliban but the Taliban was able to say
hey we're not as bad as this that's
right and enough people were like all
right [__] it yep that's exactly right
you know there was another thing too I
remember being there in like
20 7 maybe 2007 and we had come up with
this just terrible idea uh to combat
corruption right corruption is endemic
it's just a part of the culture so we
decided that the police chief in each
province would have to come from another
Province right so the police chief in a
pashun area was a Hazara for example and
the police chief in uh beluch area was
from you know the the border with
Tajikistan and they said well that way
you know there's no connection between
the police chief and the populace they
don't have anything in common so it's
going to make bribery go away and it's
going to make everybody honest no they
just started killing all the police
Chiefs they're like I'm not going to
where's this guy from he's got Asian
eyes he's not a poshu right and then
they put a bullet in his head it's like
that's a that was a dumb idea who's who
thought of
that there a lot of people who play
fantasy football with government sitting
in offices in DC and got right langly
and stuff doesn't mean they're dumb it
means that they're not thinking no and
they just have no cultural understanding
and no understanding of History I will
say that for the most part
the working
level Foreign Service officers at the
state department do have that
understanding of history and they tend
to focus on specific Geographic areas so
if you're an arabist you speak Arabic
you're going to spend probably the
entirety of your career in the Middle
East until you become an ambassador and
then you'll probably spend most of it in
the Middle East even after you've become
an ambassador and you know elsewhere in
government USA ID
CIA Pentagon forget it I never met
anybody to Pentagon spoke
Arabic they live in their own
worlds what is where where's the state
department and all this that's actually
good you bring that up because there the
state department and you've done a great
job explaining this in the past I know
bu de mon talked about this in the past
and Jim Lawler and those guys like they
will house a lot of people who maybe
work for the agency or even sometimes
the Pentagon like undercover and then
they're also there to be the diplomats
and have the embassy and you know shake
hands and kiss babies but for things
like USI a idea to happen you have the
intelligence agencies potentially using
it as like a moneya laundering operation
to get see that's the dangerous part but
does the state department know that's
happening or can they just not do
anything about it yes and yes okay yeah
there there's a formal written agreement
between the CIA and the state department
um on that addresses cover issues you
know sometimes for for for most of my
career actually for the entirety of my
career now that I'm thinking about it um
I was under what was called nominal
cover like oh where do you work ah State
Department right there was nothing to
back that up you couldn't call the state
department and say can I speak to John
and then you know they route the call to
me that just didn't exist oh you didn't
even have a cover back no no no no no no
I was declared to so many intelligence
Services it wouldn't have made it a
difference anyway so
um so there's this formal agreement
between the state department and the CIA
like there is between the the CIA and
other governmental bodies USA Aid is an
unusual situation though I never ever
encountered a CIA officer who was
embedded in usaid I don't think that
that happens um it it wouldn't make
sense anyway because really yeah because
when you're when you're embedded
you have to do that cover job for eight
hours and then you go out and do your
CIA job for eight hours that's right
so if if you're going to be given some
kind of official cover you don't want it
to be USA ID where you actually have to
do the work you know you want to
be I got to be very careful here um but
you want to be in a position where you
can sort of blend the two H yeah why do
you have to be careful here
because um the details are classified
okay yeah yeah let's not have another
trial no no no more trials for me thank
you so you got to blend the two leave
that there
now the reason I said that this is a a
problem is that to use to use a phrase
that I heard this week on the news um
usaid was was a beach head for the C in
the state department that's that's not
what USA ID is supposed to do usaid is
supposed to be you know digging water
wells and training doctors and you know
building sewage treatment plants and
electrical grids and helping people
develop it's the agency for
International Development which was like
John F Kennedy's that was the plan it
yeah usaid the Peace Corps and Vista
were all created at the same time by
John Kennedy you know was a great idea
yeah but the CIA
the CIA moved right in as soon as
Kennedy was killed by 1964 the CIA was
running covert operations out of usaid
this has all been Declassified it's all
available this is Declassified this is
Declassified it's available at the um at
the National Security archives at George
Washington University okay so for this
example since it's Declassified can you
explain what that one look like because
now I'm a bit confused cuz you're saying
you wouldn't go undercover there but
there's a they did not have they did not
have people
undercover uh at usaid what they did is
they ran covert op operations through
usaid English uh okay in
1972 Ted Kennedy wrote a letter to the
CIA and he said this is also available
Declassified online so he said I heard
that the CIA was paying Lo oan
Mercenaries
through USA ID just cutting okay payroll
checks yeah um is that true and so he
got a letter back from from Henry
Kissinger who was the Secretary of State
at the time real straight shooter too oh
yeah yeah he's never going to op gate
phenomenal guy he got an identical
letter from the CIA like identical to
the
word um saying yeah we're using usaid
essentially to launder money and pay
these Lo ocean mercenaries to fight
Communists and Kennedy's letter said did
you pay these people in
1969 and he said yeah we paid him in 69
and 70 and 71 and 72 like what are you
going to do about it
Kendy well that was just one of many
many operations that that was paid for
through
usaid here's another thing and and this
might be a better explanation I love
when John starts cooking that's great
really Chef curry with the shot keep
going there used to be a a senator
Democratic senator from Wisconsin by the
name of William
proxmire proxmire was famous for a
couple of reasons first he won the seat
that uh Joseph McCarthy vacated when he
drank himself to death okay right yeah
so he was a liberal Democrat there he is
Bill proxmire and he was famous also for
never spending a single dollar to get
reelected he he said the people of
Wisconsin know my voting record they
either like it or they don't like it and
he got elected Time After Time After
Time yeah he finally retired like in the
70s like 76 or 78 something like that
I've never heard of that before at any
point when did he retire it looks like
Senator 89 okay so he was around for a
long time from 57 to 89 so he hated
government waste more than anything in
the world and he decided to bestow an
award kind of a gag award called the
Golden Fleece award for the fleecing of
the American taxpayer and he would do it
every month every month he would call a
press conference I like to issue the
Golden Fleece award the problem
was a lot of what he identified as
government waste was actually secret CIA
programming so he couldn't say it no he
said it anyway oh he did and he didn't
get arrested this CIA was apoplectic all
bet because he would say you know $5
million to Dollars to study you know gay
monkeys in gaban and he's like what the
[__] is this this is a waste of the
taxpayers money well of course there was
no $5 million to study gay monkeys and
gaban that's just what they called it
yeah so that the CIA because you can't
like go on to Google and look for the
CIA budget it's you can't but do they
have to create like a shell company on
the other side meaning like a company
called like research for gay monkey
studies are there's really mercenaries
behind it who are like thank you for the
money there are at least hundreds of
those right okay maybe thousands so they
got to try they got to try got it yes
yeah but the thing is the cia's budget
is hidden all around the rest of the
federal budget yeah okay it's not just
in the state department not just in the
defense department or the Commerce
Department it's everywhere and so
they'll say $5 million for gay monkeys
and gaban and they'll put that at USA ID
or they'll put it in you know the
whatever some fund for the National
Geographic Society or whatever they're
not really going to spend that money on
that they're going to spend it to you
know buy weapons for lotion mercenaries
or you know bring drugs to Los Angeles
or whatever okay so let me ask a direct
question then on this that you may not
know the answer to but in theory you
could did we really spend $50 million on
condoms in mosm Beek or did that fund
some sort of like Rebel Army there you
know if that were $50,000 I'd say yeah
we we did that if it's $50 million I'd
say that's nuts and it's probably
something else okay that's making sense
now yeah so this is a tail as old as
time and they as you said there's
Declassified things involved in like
Henry Kissinger where they admit oh yeah
they're doing this and they went beyond
that I mean let's go into the into the
early 2000s please uh in
2003 we didn't do anything wrong in 2003
stop stop right there I don't know where
people found the time to get all these
was a great year there everything was
right slam dunk slam dunk it was a slam
dunk wasn't it in 2003 we
created a Facebook alternative called
zun
zuno and it just appeared in Cuba like
oh look this this this this Facebook
copy it it just appeared on the Cuban uh
internet one day yeah and uh I didn't
know they had that yeah zun zuno and so
it was supposed to um encourage Cubans
to initiate uh the equivalent of the
Arab Spring and overthrow the castros
and nobody signed up for zun zuno nobody
no they couldn't get anyone to sign up
no people were like no we're not they
didn't like drop some flyers with like
prizes no no low effort yeah weren't
interested that's how I like my
overthrows though John softly you do it
online you piss them off everyone gets
their TIY torches they have a nice
little meeting and then poof new leader
yep nothing wrong with that that's
exactly right um in in
2013 they um they infiltrated the
Bolivian uh media to try to overthrow
Evo Morales how' they do this uh they
just started buying uh
journalists you say hey how much do you
make $500 a month okay here's $5,000 WR
this article saying that Ava Morales was
caught with a six-year-old girl yeah
they're like okay I can do that how
often does stuff like that still happen
oh every single day right yeah all over
the world all over the world meaning
it's not just concentrated in one two
places of interest this stuff is
happening all the time all over the
world and you know with the with the
advance of technology too it just makes
it easier and easier although it
diffuses it because you know it's not
just ABC CBS NBC The New York Times The
Washington Post The Wall Street Journal
the LA Times now there are millions I
mean we're all journalists any any
blogger anybody any slob who rolls out
of bed in the morning and makes a
YouTube video can be a I feel a t a
journalist I'm sorry I didn't mean to
it's okay you saw my bed before we got
started no that's okay you're a pirates
hat and that's that's all that matters
hat John but keep falling
behind but yes as you were saying it
happens every day
yeah
so if we had to steal man something like
that would you say that doing cuz that
doesn't sit right with me that you're
you are infecting what's supposed to be
sources of News That's supposed to in
theory be unbiased so it just feels
dirty in every way I know what happens
to us it's same argument as earlier I
know what happens to us all the time do
you think if you had to choose poison
pill it's better to do that than it is
to actually hire Rebels to go in and
kill the people in charge that we don't
like
yes now it it'ss hard it's like what do
we do and what do we not do hard and and
your chances of success are low yeah I
mean look at look at what the Russians
were accused of doing in
2016 and what they actually did in 2016
the Democratic narrative is that the
Russians essentially bought the 2016
election for Donald Trump right that's
all been all been proven false yep yep
so what did the Russians actually do
they spent
$50,000 on YouTube ads okay none of the
YouTube ads were
political
25,000 half of it was spent after the
election was over so you have $25,000
left and they're all like memes of
kitten
and puppies and
flowers almost all of that money was
spent in states that were already
solidly red or solidly blue MH that's
not stealing the election that's
somebody some idiot wasted $50,000 like
we were looking at up here
mhm yeah so we do it the Russians do it
the Chinese do it the Cubans the
Iranians the Israelis the French the
British everybody does it so why did
they cuz we can look at that now because
so much of this has been disproven you
know it was always crazy to me there
were so many things like just in general
that if you wanted to attack Trump on
you could attack him but they had to
come up with stuff yeah why attack him
on the fake stuff that's what I'm saying
like stuff and and they made it sound
very bad I'll say that so I see why it
could make a story but they attacked him
on things that now hindsight being in
2020 it's like it was always going to
come out that this isn't real the
evidence is all there you know when you
assemble this blue ribbon panel of the
the greatest Minds in government to look
at the evidence they're going to find
the truth unless they're the warrant
commission but unless they're the
warrant commission or maybe the 911
Commission well I don't I don't want to
talk about that okay and uh no just
kidding pin put in that we're coming
back and um yeah I mean if they're if
they're legitimately doing their job
they're going to find look we we have no
evidence the Russians didn't steal the
election for Donald Trump
that's just the way it
is there was so M there were so many
people though because you're making me
think with the media thing there were so
many people in the media who were now we
can say it creating evidence oh my
Godel an example yeah I on my show one
day we played a clip of Rachel mattow
saying Russia Moscow or Putin 90 times
in the first hour of her show the night
before it was ridiculous and she was
ripping Mitt Romney for saying it four
years before that M remember that he got
like laughed off the stage oh yeah
Obama's like cold war call wants their
policy back and and everyone's like H he
said Russia and then it was like the
main keyword yeah it sure was do do you
think
that well let's get to the bigger
question here do you think that
like powers that be in the bureau Ry I
mean this is what the internet says but
do you think there is any legitimacy to
people in the
bureaucracy besides like those two
idiots at the FBI who really were
actually working to attribute things to
other places when in fact it was quite
literally them doing it to stop Donald
Trump from getting into
Power boy that's a good question yeah
you know how looks yeah regardless of
politics yous yeah you know honestly I
have to say probably yes yeah yeah
probably and and that's a surprise to me
because when I when I worked at the
CIA we generally had no idea what our
colleagues politics were genuinely I sat
next to this one guy for six years I
didn't have the foggiest idea if he was
a Democrat a Republican or an
independent no idea there was a woman I
worked with this is in like
96 and she got in trouble like written
up because she put a Bob Dole for
president bumper sticker in her
cubicle oh wow and they're like that has
to come down and you're getting written
up and you have to go to HR and you know
we work for the for the country we don't
choose sides that's how it used to be at
the FBI as well and that really seemed
to change dramatically around
2016 what do you think it was do well
let me even ask a hypothetical one there
because I always wonder this I'm like
obviously I know Trump says a lot of
[__] and like you know he's an outsider
and all this but like do you think that
there's some sort of intelligence I
don't know what it would be that they
know about him that they think is just
so
dangerous that they're willing to
completely lift the veil on
their not caring about these elections
and no and saying like [__] it get him
out of there somebody would have leaked
it you know going back to um to the um
Christopher steel report you know I
worked with Chris steel wait this is the
guy who had the piss memo right right
yeah he he was an MI uh six uh officer
you worked with him yeah we did an
operation together in in London in the
90s and the funny thing about it is he
was like the guy at MI6 that all the
other MI6 guys wanted to be like that's
how highly respected he was I I enjoy
Christopher steel golden showers yeah
okay please continue so I have I have a
theory he went
from the James Bond kind of officer that
that every MI6 guy wanted to be to this
caricature
because when you're collecting
intelligence when you're an operations
officer collecting intelligence no
matter how outrageous the intelligence
might be you send it back to your
headquarters and the analysts go over it
and the analysts say this is [__]
this is great this is a possibility this
is a probability you just turn over the
analysts so if he had been at MI6 and A
source told him that Donald Trump paid
Russian prostitutes to pee on Barack
Obama's Hotel
bed um the analysts would say this is
stupid and it wouldn't get published
because there's no other information to
corroborate this
mhm but in private practice there is no
team of analysts to go over the the
intelligence cuz he was out by then he
was out by then and he was
paid by the Clinton campaign although
there were reports that he was initially
hired by the Ted Cruz campaign and then
Cruz walked away from it liying Ted
uhhuh and then Hillary said we'll take
it so there was no team of analysts to
vet the information and to tell the
Clinton campaign this is nonsense this
is true this is maybe this is I don't
know we have to ask other questions find
other sources there was nobody to do
that and so he did what he always did at
MI6 he just write it up and sent it in
and then let the next group figure out
if it's true or not you think it's just
literally because he may not have
endorsed it he just had what he found
and he didn't have government analysts
on the other side so he said they'll
take care of that yeah I think that's
exactly what happened now how all right
back up a second how were you working
with this
guy was this was this the Greek stuff
yeah oh [__] okay can you talk about
this at all in
generalities that's good enough I became
the master of the old files on Greek
terrorism I I took this issue so
seriously it actually cost me my first
marriage I was obsessed with Greek
terrorism yep and then they tried to
kill me in Athens you told that story
so I would go through these files these
files some of them were 25 years old
just looking for a lead a lead that
maybe had been overlooked 10 20 25 years
ago and I found a lead it was a
connection between the Greeks and Carlos
The
Jackal and nobody had ever talked to
this guy so I'm like where is this guy
we don't have any idea where this guy is
so which
guy oh the connection got it got it yeah
so I wrote a cable to headquarters and I
said I've identified this guy that I
think is the middleman between the
Greeks and Carlos The
Jackal um do we have any idea where he
is I think he's probably in Lebanon I
said I get a cable back and they said no
he's he's living in
London I said how in the heck is he
living in London they said he converted
to Christianity married some English
woman and he's living in
London and I said I got I got to see him
a Carlos De Jackal plug living openly in
London MH can you tell people who Carlos
De Jackal was by the way who caros the
Jackal was the most infamous and
deadliest independent terrorist of the
1970s there there was a movie based on
on his exploits called uh The Day of the
Jackal it's a classic 70s film and the
reason why I say
independent um terrorist is he did this
for ideology he was a communist but like
an Ardent yes hardcore Bolshevik kind of
communist believer he was Venezuelan by
birth his name was um ilich Ramirez
Sanchez um his n deare was Carlos The
Jackal and he was just impossible to
find but he did some of the most
outrageous terrorist attacks he and his
men just
simultaneously opened fire on the
airports in Rome and Vienna killed I
forget what a dozen two dozen people
whatever it was the most outrageous
operation that he carried out was there
was an OPEC oil ministers meeting in
Vienna Austria okay so all the me all
the Ministers of oil he loves those guys
yeah loves those guys all the Ministers
of oil from all of the opet countries
and he kidnapped all of them at the same
time
he was a gangster I'm not going to lie I
mean this dude was different my God and
the OPEC countries are like okay how
many hundreds of millions do you want to
give us our people back yeah and they
paid we've talked about his capture it's
it's actually quite exciting that was
Billy wall Billy W yeah in cartoon but
anyway um I wrote a cable to um
headquarters and they wrote a cable to
the Brits and they said hey we've got a
guy in Athens you know this is what he's
working on this is what he wants can he
come and uh and talk to this this guy
and they said sure but you know as per
protocol we're going to have a guy from
MI5 and a guy from MI6 go with him and I
said cool so they set up this meeting of
all freaking places it was at the
Hardrock Cafe in London with you
know through the whole meeting I
couldn't I couldn't even hear myself but
he did that on purpose cuz he he
genuinely believed I was going to shoot
him in the meeting MH he was scared to
death shaking mouth all dry and I kept
saying I don't mean you any harm I
understand that you've straightened out
your life he said I found God I became a
Greek Orthodox Christian I married this
beautiful woman he was living in some
housing project outside it was
bad so I so he's living poor yeah he was
poor and I said I don't care about
anything but Carlos I want to know about
Carlos and the weapons that went to the
Greeks
well he ended up being less valuable
than I had hoped we met I don't know
four or five times but um but chisle sat
in on every single meeting and we kind
of struck up a professional friendship I
had a great deal of respect for the guy
and then fast
forward what 15 years yeah and they're
talking about the steel dossier and I I
was like that can't be the Chris steel
from MI6 now he's Christopher steel
right yeah and it was I recognized him
on TV I was like you've got to be
kidding me how could somebody so highly
respected so professional get stuck in
this political quicksand up to his neck
and the conclusion that I finally came
to was he did exactly what he used to do
at MI6 yeah just thinking well there's
this whole team you know there has to be
this whole team in Washington to analyze
the information just like I had this
whole team in London to analyze the
information they paid me to collect it
they didn't pay me to analyze it so here
it is Hillary Clinton knew it was
[__] he had to but he has his head
in the sand with that thinking that you
know they're going to run with anything
just to be like oh look he's a Russian
asset I'll tell you what as a as an
intelligence collector if I had one
source say something that was utterly
outrageous that no other source
corroborated I would never have included
it in the
report you know I I asked an officer one
time in the Middle East I was doing a
paper and there was a a foreign woman's
name who came up
repeatedly and so I didn't know anything
about her and we didn't have anything in
the files so I send what's called a a um
no I won't say what it's called anyway I
sent a cable saying I'm working on this
study for the for the National Security
Council and This Woman's name keeps
popping up I don't know who she is
there's nothing in the files can you
collect on her and one of the officers
responded Yes I can collect I was like
great and I I put the paper on hold
waiting for him to trigger a meeting
with his with his source so he can ask
the source course tell me all about this
woman yeah I get the report back the
entire report was about how much she
loved hot
dogs that she would put them with
mustard and sometimes with onions and
sometimes with relish and then every
time she goes to the states she has hot
dogs and she asked the some airline to
ship in Hot Dogs I'm like are you
[__] kidding me I waited for two
weeks for this report I can't send this
to the president yeah oh and by the way
this woman who we think may be procuring
weapons for this terrorist group she
really really loves hot
dogs I was
Furious but sometimes the collectors
just aren't thinking about the end
result they're like oh you want to know
about the woman here she loves these hot
dogs Chris steel oh you want to know
about uh uh Obama and Trump yeah Trump
hired hookers to piss on Obama's bed
isn't that hilarious it's like no do you
have any idea what you just did to our
election yeah have you tried to reach
out to him
you know I talked about it with a friend
uh back in 2016 and then I thought nah
I'm going to leave well enough alone and
I've been back to London I don't know
six eight times since then but I I
haven't you don't stay with him no no
it's too much too much trouble
intelligence agencies though like
because it always comes back to us when
I talk with you guys obviously they have
these names for certain alliances in air
quotes you got the five eyes all the
English countries and they're friends
yeah right yeah we are leg they are but
is anyone really friends are you really
friends with someone if the minute they
walk out the door you [__] attached a
microphone to their ass so you can hear
them fart oh no in in the case of five
eyes it's you know I didn't believe this
when they first announced the creation
of the five eyes but we were instructed
to open the books and give them
literally everything to the point where
there are five eyes officers sitting at
NSA FBI CIA sitting there with you they
have a desk all the books all the books
not just the books that sit in the main
part of the library and then there's a
hatch that takes you downstairs really
no they're going to be compartmented
operations but it's not just they can't
see it because they're five eyes they're
foreign Nationals they can't see it
because nobody else can see it but maybe
six people you know what I mean which is
a lot yeah it's compartmentalized like
you said but it's a lot there's a lot of
things like that
yeah yeah do you think they have the
same policy for us oh yeah really
MH that surprises me it surprised me
when it was first announced you know we
had very poor relations with New Zealand
for example for many years Ronald Reagan
um withdrew the CIA station Chief from
New Zealand and closed the station there
in
1982 in a fit of peak for what why
because they would not allow a nuclear
powerered submarine into port
yeah you know what [__] them how dare
they yeah that's we're gonna Park our
nuke where we want it that's what Reagan
said don't shoot the Lord of the Rings
there and then and then in
91 it's like six weeks before we we
attacked uh Iraq to push them out of
Kuwait I was instructed to brief the
prime minister of New Zealand and I was
like New Zealand I thought they were on
the [__] list and they're like yeah well
it's war time we're going to we're going
to try to rehabilitate them oh you know
[__] it I even got invited to the
ambassador's house for dinner afterwards
it was so much fun of course you did you
didn't plant a bug there no you sure
positive you can tell me and the food
was great in New Zealand it was
delicious at the ambassador's residence
the New Zealand Wasington no it was a
lot of fruits I remember that fruit yeah
that's cool it was nice so they're
really friend I'm I'm surprised to hear
that yeah five eyes is the real deal all
right I'm going to put a pin in one
thing because I want to come back to
that whole friendship thing with someone
else but I don't want to lose the last
important part of this USA conversation
which is how it's being uncovered right
so I wish we lived in a world where
Optics didn't matter but they do how
things look unfortunately are often more
important than how they actually are and
you just had an election where certainly
like a lot of people voted for Trump and
and voted for going in and fixing some
of the swamp and whatever and he's
trying to follow through on some of that
and I respect that MH as someone who is
a fan of Elon Musk I always say this I'm
not a fan boy I don't sit here and
gargle the balls of every [__] thing
he does he's a genius I love his
companies I think there's so much
exciting [__] I think he's a funny guy I
think he's entertaining I think he has
some pretty good ideas I disagree with
some of the ways he public L goes about
things I also know he as he stated like
he has autism so there you know there's
a certain there can be an edge to him
right there can be an edge to him the
Optics though of the richest guy not
named Vladimir Putin or some long sality
last name in the world having full
access to all of these programs
including I think even some stuff in the
treasury or whatever and the IRS right
now he's not technically elected though
a lot of people did elect Donald Trump
with him being attached to it I will
defend him on that the Optics though of
of him being in charge of that is not
the best to me cuz I I almost wonder if
it defeats the purpose of what I like
him doing here which is this minus like
it just being him doing it does that
make sense I'm glad you said the I I'm
glad you use the word Optics because
it's important in this in this uh case a
friend of mine posted on Facebook the
other
day something about you know it was
illegal for Trump to appoint m
and I was like no it wasn't yeah it
wasn't no it's not at all illegal his
title is adviser to the President right
okay anybody can be appointed adviser to
the president and when you're appointed
adviser to the president you're given
you're given the Necessities to carry
out the task so he's got you know all
the clearances that he needs he has you
know a small staff um I think his staff
is uh a problem it's like Five Guys in
their early 20s who don't really know
what they're doing that was probably not
the best choice but he's perfectly
within his rights to be doing what he's
doing I would prefer like you that he
not muck around with my personal
information that's at the IRS or the
department of the treasury or whatever
but with that said his task from the
president is to take a machete to the
federal budget and I have to say and I
can't believe I'm saying it but I have a
lot of respect for that
yeah I was reserving judgment until just
a few days ago when the president
announced much to the shock of every
Lefty in America that he's ordered musk
to cut the Pentagon budget by 8% a year
for five consecutive years that has
never been done in American history ever
it's incredible to me yes a letter went
out to all CIA employees the other day
saying we're not immune layoffs are
coming there hasn't been a layoff at
this CIA since
1977 so this is serious they mean
business and I think that's a good thing
I do too is it problematic though that
one guy's kind of spearheading it and
just like this isn't his fault but he is
the richest guy in this country yeah
it's a bad look I I will I will admit to
you it's a bad look you know I mentioned
offline and you told me to
wait actually met him one time yeah
John's got it like every time it really
does happen off camera people every time
we bring up anything he's like let me
give you an example I know that guy and
you're like wait how do you know Abraham
Lincoln I was there April 14th what a
night every [__] time I got a Lincoln
story too I'll tell you in a minute
godamn
um no you'll get a kick out of it so are
you Ser as a as a hobby most people
don't know this most people who know me
don't know this but as a hobby I like to
write television Pilots right just for
fun and I have an agent and a manager
and an entertainment lawyer and I have
sold eight of them over the years and
one of them actually made it to Pilot
right under your name yeah uhuh I have
an IMDb page it's like this long yeah
let's get it so
um I had an idea for a news show and I
mentioned it to a buddy of mine who's in
the industry and he said oh wait a
minute he says before you pitch it my
best friend from high school just became
the president of NBC
uh Ben I don't remember his last name he
was the he was the producer of the uh of
the office he said let's pitch it to Ben
uh and
uh yeah see I did all kinds of I did all
kinds of stuff there true and self I've
got like 60 something True Lies yeah
true lies I was the script uh script
coordinator come on yeah
fun wait you were on Kill the Messenger
the movie yeah oh you were an advisor
for that right advis about whatever Gary
web yeah yeah whacked him I did Bruno I
did From Paris With Love with John
Travolta oh my God yeah you've talked
about Bruno before yeah yeah yeah it's
fun I do all kinds of stuff all right so
you were saying your friend the NBC he
said yeah I got this friend Ben he was
my best friend from high school he just
became the president of NBC let me call
him we could pitch the show to him I
said great so he calls him and Ben says
hey I'm going to be at dinner at the
white house uh Obama had just got
elected and he had this big fundraiser
um for wealthy Jewish Democrats and so
he said the dinner ends at 9: let's meet
at the bar at the hey Adams hey Adams
hotel across the street from the White
House at uh at 9: we said great so 9:00
comes he's running a little late he
calls my buddy and says um hey I'm
running late I'll be there at 9:15 do
you mind if I bring a friend we said no
the more than marrier so uh they come at
9:15
and
um my friend Rich and Ben are like
hugging each other oh my God it's been
so long you look great oh you've had
such success you're the producer of the
office and now you're NBC it's amazing
blah blah blah and then they sit down
and and Ben says uh this is my friend
Elon and I said hi Elon nice to meet you
I shake his hand I said uh and Rich says
this is John I said hi Ben nice to meet
you this is like 08 09 oh yeah very very
beginning of 09 so um we're sitting
there and Rich and Ben are like hey you
remember this girl we both banged in
high school and hey remember this
teacher we both hated remember so and so
had this party and and Elan and I are
just sitting there looking at these guys
like I this conversation means nothing
to me so finally I go so Elon what do
you do for a
living as soon as the words came out of
my mouth he goes like this he goes oh
oh I have this passion for technology
and I created this company called PayPal
and then I sold it for like a billion
dollars and then I used the money and I
bought another company called Tesla and
then I I have another company called
SpaceX and we're going to go to Mars and
we're going to colonize Mars and we're
going to put a big dome and it's going
to have oxygen in it and people are
going to go up there and they're going
to colonize Mars some are going to die
but they're going to be heroes they're
going to be heroes we're going to
colonize Mars and I'm I'm looking at
them and I go wait a minute wait a
minute are you Elon
Musk and he goes yeah oh my God and I go
like the Thomas Edison of our time he
goes I don't know I guess so but anyway
we're going to go to Mars and there's
going to be this giant Dome and we're
going to build buildings in there and
we're going to be able to farm and we're
going to have
oxygen I never pitched the show I never
spoke about the show the whole rest of
the two hours was him tell talking about
colonizing Mars and this is you said
this at the very beginning of 2009
shortly after January of 2009 okay so
literally days after Obama yeah days he
had been president for days you know
what's you know what's crazy about this
there is a very famous story about Elon
Musk and please correct me in the
comments if I have the date wrong but
I'm pretty sure I got it right Christmas
Eve 2008 weeks before this yeah very
famous story Elon was up to the brims
because of the financial crisis he had
Tesla and he had SpaceX and he was told
by all of his advisers you know they
they had money due they had been trying
to get raises in couldn't get it in the
companies were going to put they said
you have to pick one if you pick one
there's like a 90% chance or something
that it will survive if you pick both
they'll both die oh my God and he said I
can't let one go I guess we're just GNA
have to die oh my God and he picked it
and then money came in like five days
later they were able to so he's talking
with you in this hotel tell weeks after
like nothing's going on when he just
made the most insane decision of his
career and for years afterwards I just
assumed he was Jewish because he had
been at this fundraiser well because it
was a Jewish fundraiser you know Jewish
democ you say where's your yamaka no I
just and in fact somebody corrected me
years later and they said musk isn't
Jewish I said are you sure because he he
was at this fundraiser for Jewish
Democrats he's like no he just went just
to go you know I that you call him too
Elon I was like yeah so Elan what do you
do for a living oh my God I didn't know
he looks like Vaguely Familiar to me but
I didn't know who the heck he was that's
crazy when you met him is crazy to me
yeah like a long time ago but that's on
brand like he's so like ah [__] it let's
go so he could just whatever that guy
does to be able to compartmentalize in
every aspect of his life except when
someone pisses him off with a meme is
incredible
like true it's unbelievable cuz I guess
it just takes a different kind of well
it definitely takes a different kind of
marine to be a guy like that without a
doubt you know Forbes came out with a uh
she'll reach out to him for the pardon
by the way you know I wish I could get
to him I don't know how to get to him
we'll get to him stick with me okay
let's let's work on that I'll tell you
something offline that's very important
about that um Abraham Lincoln here we go
I am a Lincoln
collector um over like the car or the
guy no the guy over many years I have
bought things associated with Abraham
Lincoln at auction I have uh I have a
blood soaked piece of the pillowcase
that he died on come on yeah I do framed
uh yeah framed I I bought it at Saab it
still got his blood on it soaked with
blood um I have an 11 and a half inch
strip of the wallpaper from the room
that he died in at the Peterson guest
house I have a Swatch of Mrs Lincoln's
uh dress that she wore to his funeral
what's a Swatch a just a scrap oh of her
black dress I have a a piece of the wood
that made the Gallows that the
conspirators were were hung from That's
a crazy story by the way I I buy all
this stuff at at auction like serious
auctions and it's all about provenance
you know provenance provenance is you
have to be able to to document from
Lincoln himself how it got to you M so
the the blood soaked pillowcase piece um
Mr Peterson who owned the house that he
died in took the pillowcase and cut it
into pieces with the scissors and he
gave the Doctor Who fished the bullet
out of Lincoln's brain the piece he gave
it to his daughter who married the
governor of Indiana and then it passed
down through their family until they
sold it at sopes and I bought it
right whoa so that's provenance so you
can prove that it is what it says it is
so summer of
2009 I have my boys for the summer I I
had two sons at the time well I had I
had more than just I had three sons and
a daughter but my two from my oldest
from my first second marriage my second
marriage at that point so we went to
Baltimore the whole family went to
Baltimore because they had this thing
called the sideshow Museum and it was a
museum of circus freak shows from the
1800s like stuff that had been in these
circus s shows they had like some N9
foot tall woman she's mummified the the
Amazon they called her they had a
Jackalope you know stuff like most of
it's funny just silly stuff but they
have this shadow box hanging on the wall
and there's a dried out turd in it and
it says it's Abraham Lincoln's final
turd come on so it says on the card it
said when he arrived at Ford's Theater
he had to drop a deuce and so before he
got seated he went to the men's room and
he dropped a deuce in the chamber pot
and then he went back to watch the play
and he got shot and someone fished it
out somebody had the presence of mind to
fish it out and they saved the presence
of mine or the sickness well there are a
lot of Lincoln collectors out there it's
very competitive so technically the last
[__] he takes is in the bed after he
dies well technically you're right
technically yes you're right so unless
he got it all out the first time all
right so uh thank
you so this place was run down and it
was dirty and the owner had a cat the
place smelled of cat and I see an
article in the Washington post about six
months later saying it's going out of
business and they're going to auction
everything off so I told my wife I'm
buying that
turd she's like oh no you're not I said
oh yes I am I'm buying in that turd John
what do what does 144 year old turd look
like it was all dried out and there was
a kernel of rice sticking out of
it and he how do you preserve that he
had chicken and rice for his last meal
that was his last meal I could plant the
rice in there if I wanted to how how do
you preserve that it was just air dried
they just stuck it in a shadow box it
was pinned to the shadow box I heard
that but that's all they did yeah it
dries out
it doesn't like go moldy or anything
so my wife and I actually had a strong
disagreement about this I wonder why
she's like there's no provenance right
just because it was in the sideshow
Museum that's not provenance you have to
be able to and I said I know what
provenance is so I go to the
auction and I I top out at 1,200 bucks
I'm just I can't go over 1,200 for this
thing
it ends up going for five grand oh my
God so the Washington Post reporter is
there and he's like there was this turd
and it went for $5,000 spirited bidding
they
said so the guy that ended up buying it
sends it to some company for a DNA
sample and what they found was it had
like microscopic bits of Necco wafer in
it you know what a Neco wafer is do I
look like I know what Necco wafer is
John it's the most disgusting candy
that's ever been created it's from
Pittsburgh wow that sounds about right
and they're all pastel colors they're
disgusting they're little Wafers little
round circles they look like buttons but
Necco Wafers weren't invented until
1880 it wasn't his [__] it wasn't his it
was just some guys some random guy's
turd that somebody paid $5,000 for I
thanked my lucky stars that I didn't get
it that's called
Darwinism to whoever spent $5,000 on
anyone's
[__] right but
that's you imagine like the Washington
Post reporters like Joby works so yeah
so why'd you buy this [__] oh my God I
would have called him like Joby Joby we
can't be bid against each other oh my
God how far back do you go with Joby uh
07 was he calling you about that he was
one of the first guys to interview me
wow yeah yeah I think he mentioned it
last time he was in here he's a good guy
yeah I like Jo he's a good solid solid
reporter yes mhm he's he's so unafraid
to be the sober voice in the room and
tell people [__] they don't want to hear
that's right and also sometimes like he
speaks openly about like look you're
still working with sources that have
they got their motives right and so
sometimes you're going to get backed
information that turns out to give
exactly what they want to get out there
that's exactly a lot of journalists cuz
it it's just a reality of that
profession it's a reality of even what I
do here I don't know every [__]
person that comes in here and what
they're trying to do and this is one of
the reasons why I respect Joby War so
much um he's not the kind of of
journalist who's going to just take a
CIA press release and gist it he has
sources yeah human
sources that he can use to to either
confirm or or deny information yeah I I
I love talk when I was a fan of him
before I ever brought him in here
because I read his books his books are
incredible his books are fantastic the
the the host bombing oh man yeah you got
to call him and ask him what he's
working on right now I'm not allowed to
tell you okay but I think we were
talking off camera earlier about
something else and I think it'd be
something you would be very interesting
oh excellent yeah it's it's really cool
stuff small world yeah but so you're how
did you get into being a Lincoln
collector like were you just obsessed
with the guy when you were a kid yeah
yeah the greatest president in American
history as far as I'm concerned he's
definitely top three the kind of person
that we should want to be like the only
thing I ever got out bid on that I
really kick myself over there was a
gigantic uh Lincoln auction at Heritage
auctions in Dallas back in 2009 and I
was outbid on the original key to his
tomb I couldn't get that that went for
big bucks what what kind of bucks we
talking uh went for close to 10 10 grand
I think I went up to like 3600
3,800 and my wife is like it's a
freaking key yeah
it's just a key yeah you could buy like
a lot of gon with that yeah something
yeah so do you have like a Lincoln room
no I just I have it framed and then I
put it up on the wall I've got a I've
got a ballot from Ohio from the 1860
election that has Lincoln on the on the
ballot that's a lot higher on my list
than [__] but you know God damn it John
this did you ever see that documentary
it just makes when you were saying
provenance it makes me think about it
because I've never asked anyone about
that I just watched it but you ever see
the documentary The Lost
Leonardo yes and I don't think that's a
Leonardo okay I think Muhammad bin
Salman got ripped off I think he might
have too $500 million just for context
for people there was a
piece down in a New Orleans auction this
is I don't know maybe a decade ago
something like that yeah what's that
it's it's Salvador Mundi yeah yeah the
Salvador Mundi and actually lesie can
you pull it up Salvatore Mundi m u n d
and you'll be able to see the picture
and so there there's apparently these
guys like this is a real job that exists
where there it is they just go to
auctions we have it up on the screen
right now they just go to auctions all
over the world wherever it is and they
try to find slips cracks right where
something slipped through the crack oh
my God I would love to do that it's such
a cool job and so these guys out of New
York I forget their name they they two
of them they went down to the show in
New Orleans and they see this picture
and they didn't go like oh that's a
Leonardo they just went something about
this is crazy because we see it on the
screen if we can pull it up one more
time or less this is it remastered I'll
explain the context as how that happened
but when they found it it was like torn
apart you kind of yeah you kind of had
to like like sift through it to see what
was there and apparently there's all
kinds of ways things can be restored so
wow that's perfect Le we got it so oh I
see down in the bottom left it's all
messed up yes yeah see that ex actually
yeah see the example on the far left up
up one ORS right there so people can see
that this is what I believe what it
initially looked like but you can see
there from an art perspective you look
at that and you go there is something
there that looks interesting it was
selling for like I don't know [__] $
thousand dollar or maybe less and these
guys are like all right yeah you can get
an old Master painting uh 17th century
16th century for 1,500 bucks especially
if they don't know who painted it
exactly right School of or circle of you
know so and so yeah so this was really
fascinating for me to learn about but
they bring it back to New York and
there's a whole underground you know
system of experts who can determine down
to the paint stroke yes with high
accuracy if something's attributable to
someone so they take it to this woman
who I forget her name but her husband he
he had passed away he was like the most
famous art something or other I'll [__]
up what what the official title was but
he was an expert on this stuff and she
was an expert on it because of him so
she starts looking through it and I
forget what her logic was but suddenly
it like Came Upon her she's like holy
[__] this is Leonardo so they commission
her to retouch it up so it goes from the
old one to the new one that we showed
like a few minutes ago and actually
looks real and they started marketing it
as a Leonardo and very quickly there was
a famous reporter I forget his name from
The New York Times who was instantly
like no [__] this that's not a Leonardo
and people started fighting over it but
long story short skipping all the middle
parts along the way it ends up going to
a soues auction in New York City where
there is the auctioneers up there a
whole crowd and then there's a silent
like crew of dudes on the phone yes who
are all like American New York attorneys
or something they're taking the bids by
uh proxy and you don't know who it is
and suddenly the bid goes up to like 450
million or something and they're like
winner so it's the most expensive piece
ever sold and it floats up later that it
is most likely MBS who bought it and now
they're like certain that he bought it
yeah and there are many people who are
still like yo that's not a Leonardo
could maybe they were saying maybe it
could have been a student of his which
isn't worth nearly as much right but the
Lou wanted to put the painting on
display in the Leonardo exhibit because
there's like 15 or 16 known leonardos
yes and there was supposedly this they
weren't admitting it was NBS they were
talking with but there was this
underground conversation oh we're going
to get it we're going to get it we're
going to get it and then eventually he
they didn't because NBS wanted it put
next to the Mona Lisa so that
symbolically people would assume it had
the same level of like importance as the
monis yeah yeah so it's like this whole
thing but the provenance is what they
didn't have they didn't know who it
passed from and all that so how heck
does it get to New Orleans you know
there was just a a two-part HBO series
uh not a series a two-part HBO
documentary on Leonardo um that goes
through his entire life and he traveled
a decent bit for you know the late 16th
century um but when I say travel I mean
between Rome Milan Venice you know
Florence yeah Naples that was pretty
much it and pretty much all of his work
stayed there and in
France and that's it how in the heck did
that end up in New Orleans I mean it's
been a lot of years things can happen
the world has certainly changed I could
see it it just it gets really weird and
that one I tend to believe it's not a
Leonardo I it's just some of the I
understand where that lady was coming
from because part of it could be a
little bit of confirmation bias because
she's looked at so much crazy art or
whole career and you know finding a
Leonardo is like finding a [__]
golden Charizard like you're not fing
that thing yeah it's what everybody
fantasizes about in that uh in that line
yeah he was something else though you
you ever read isaacson's biography of
him no so good really oh he was he was
he was a God I mean he could just he was
a true polymath who just yeah he was
who's a rebel but he could do everything
did you know that he only wrote
backwards yes I did not know that until
I saw this documentary yeah I fre
actually I haven't read the biography in
a while he was obsessed with the idea of
people stealing his Communications yes
and so he only wrote backwards yeah they
had that in The Da Vinci Code where they
part of the code that they're uncovering
Dan Brown wrote that in the book where
it's like you had to hold it up to a
mirror to see yeah [__] crazy like
bro it's like it's
like it's like James Madison James
Madison could write Greek with his right
hand and Latin with his left hand at the
same time what is that I know what is
that it's it's some kind of glitch in
your brain do you think that because
you've been around some crazy people in
your life you think some people are
literally just born physically different
and we just can't see it yeah I do I do
yeah yeah crazy I think that's the only
way you explain like an Elon
Musk right is it oh that's what I was
going to say so in Forbes last week they
said he's worth
$446 billion now he's not just the
richest man in the world he's the
richest man in the world by 100% outside
of Saudi Arabia and Vladimir Putin yeah
cuz we don't really know we don't have
any idea they're laughing over there for
like 440 that's cute yeah that's right
that is right so optically not the best
that maybe he's the kind of guy in
charged with it but the idea of what
they're doing I think is a good is music
to both of our ears right now do you
think that could
go I mean I love the idea of slashing
the waste right me too do you think it
could do you think that there are things
that he won't get access to from maybe
an intelligence perspective or something
like that that could lead to him
accidentally slashing some things that
we actually do
need probably not because I think if
that were to be the case people like
John Ratcliffe and Tulsa gabard would go
to the president and say listen just
between us there's this operation
there's this you know
program it needs to be
protected and they would be okay well
that's the other question that I was
going to ask you you just siphon right
into it someone like Tulsi gabard I like
Tulsi from what what I've heard so
you're a fan too I am a fan I wrote
about it a couple of weeks ago what why
do you like
her she's got guts first of all she's
qualified which is which is wonderful
yeah and she's got the guts to stand up
to people she stood up to the DNC she
stood up to the Democratic leadership in
congress she's a lieutenant colonel in
the Army I guess now it's the Army
Reserve um
but oh I mean that all of that is good
what I what I was also thinking is that
she's a supporter of transparency she
supported uh uh Ed Snowden she's been
supportive of Julian Assange she said a
couple nice things about me I don't know
her well enough to actually you know ask
her for a favor or anything but i' I've
met once or twice we can work on that I
hope so I've tried I've reached out a
number of times we'll get working thank
God now I won't say it on the air but
anyway we protect our friends in New
Jersey we got you don't worry thank you
so I'm I'm
optimistic I love that so many important
Democrats accuse her of being a Russian
St f a Syrian stoe why did they say this
because she bucks the official DNC
line yeah you know she went to she went
to Syria and met with Bashar al-assad
good he's a leader yeah he's a leader I
want people to be meeting with I mean
back then when he was still in Syria I
wanted them to meet with Bashar al-assad
and also when the United States said
when Barack Obama said Bashar alassad
gassed his own people we gave him this
red line we said don't cross then he
gassed his own people well there were
12 uh United Nations whistleblowers that
say that that gas attack did not come
from the Syrian government it came and
these were the inspectors who were on
the ground they said it came from
Al-Qaeda Al-Qaeda uh fired that Al-Qaeda
uhhuh but remember we're friends with
al-Qaeda in Syria we just sent a whole
delegation from the state department to
meet with the new leader of Syria who's
Al-Qaeda and and the co-founder of Isis
by the way and we lifted the $10 million
Bounty that we had on his
head so it interfered with our with our
plans all right we got to take this
Rabbit Hole real quick we'll come back
to Tulsi because you just took a Middle
Road and what I mean by that is when
this Syria conversation comes up we've
done a lot of podcasts where it gets
discuss in one way or the other Joby
Warick wrote a great book on it that has
more of the you know Assad did it point
and he lays out a lot of good evidence
for that people cook him for it all the
time and try to say it's [__] but
like he's going with what he knows the
two arguments though are that Assad did
it or then the saers argument of like oh
no the CIA did it which I I've never
seen good evidence for that but you're
say you just took a Middle Road and you
said another Rogue element yeah may have
done this and you know I got to tell you
may maybe I'm glassing glossing over it
in my memory but I don't remember
reading about at any point
whistleblowers yeah these opcw whistle
came out yeah and they all ended up
getting fired but they're the ones that
said that it was Al-Qaeda it was the
nusra front that did it yeah what was
what was their evidence of that they
were on the ground testing and they said
that there was no evidence that a
missile had been launched from the
Syrian side from the Syrian government
side so this is after it gets done
obviously they're going through the
residue and and what what reason would
Assad have to to to turn to chemical
weapons especially after he had
specifically been told by the United
States that this was a red line which
turned out to be [__] anyway we
didn't do anything that's right like
better not cross this line okay you
crossed it well then you better not
cross this new line come on Barack
Obama yeah Obama we've talked about that
a bunch Obama I've mixed emotions on
that one because first of all that was a
really stupid thing to say
MH secondly afterwards he had to try to
like clean that up politically after it
was all said and done at home and that
was messy how he did that however you
know what it's like when your pride gets
hit oh yeah you know he said something
stupid he should have never [__] said
that's right and his pride was like [__]
you we're gonna bomb him yeah which
would have started a new war and there
was because the Russians were already
based there yeah exactly I I wasn't even
going to go there but that's just
another layer to it and he apparently
the way I understand it is that he did
there was a work around here where he
didn't have to go to Congress to get
pass to take certain action that would
have started a war he could have
effectively like said I'm I said red
line I'm protect my pride and at the
last minute now he thought Congress was
going to agree with him he was very
wrong about that but he said [__] it
let's do it right let's put it through
Congress they voted like 400 to 100
against it or something whatever it was
something like that against it and he
couldn't do it and I at least respect
the fact that once he had the L he
didn't he moved on double the L that's
right that's right I agree would have
been bad to get involved in something
there but we kind of you know if it
wasn't Syria we still did
with what ended up happening with Isis
because of what was born in a lot of
there too MH have you ever been to
Syria no uh oh wasn't on my list of
vacation spots it's one of the most
fabulous places I've ever that's what I
hear but not in my life abely amazing no
no it's too dangerous it's probably
going to remain too dangerous for a long
time friendliest people best food
incredible history I mean you know you
go to Greece you see the you see the
Parthenon you go to Rome you see the
Coliseum you go to Syria you go to
Damascus and the stuff that you're
looking at is mentioned in the bible yes
that's how old it is so much hisory W I
loved it loved every minute of it what
do you think's going to happen
there
um in the near term nothing good okay in
the longer
term I could
see slow development they've been racked
by War for so long I don't think anybody
wants more war at this at this point um
the the unknown is that the
Iranians and the Russians were
humiliated by what happened with Assad
it happened so quickly you know I
remember I remember um it was exactly
one week seven days before Assad was
overthrown he and his family got on a
plane and went to Moscow and people
started saying oh my God he's running
away he's running to Moscow but then he
returned the next day to Damascus but he
left his family in Moscow and then that
same plane made three more trips to
Moscow over the course of the week
presumably to take out money and artwork
and personal effects and Furniture
whatever and then at the end of that
week he went back to Moscow and stayed
so this was a humiliation for the
Russians because they had military bases
there including a major Naval base and
remember the day he was overthrown the
Russians made this announcement that
they hoped that the new government of
Syria would respect Russian bases in
Syria ah they just ran right over the
bases yeah and took them more
importantly than than you know Russian
embarrassment is this was the Iranian
pipeline to Hezbollah and then by extend
by extension to to Hamas so the Iranian
weapons and and cash and all the stuff
that the Iranians were sending went
across Northern
Iraq uh and across Syria and then from
Syria to Lebanon and then you know
there's through a more informal pipeline
from Syria to Jordan to Hamas or Syria
to Lebanon to Hamas and it's gone now
like like that just like that it's gone
and at the same time the Israelis
essentially decapitated hez balah they
killed Hassan nalah three days later
they killed the guy who replaced tassan
Masa and now there's a guy nobody ever
heard of and half of his uh his Fighters
have been killed or wounded so for a
while there's going to be pretty much no
Hezbollah not
meaningfully and Syria's Syria's economy
though that's a wreck it's been a wreck
because essentially I I was talking to
this guy on the phone that we trying to
get in for a podcast who met with a
in like 2012 he's a Syrian wow and told
him what was going to happen here you
know if he didn't change his ways or
whatever the [__] you told him yeah so
we're working on getting him in here he
has to get like approval to do it so
we'll see if that Happ that would be
exciting yeah it would be really cool
he's he's very very smart but you know
what he's saying is that yeah the whole
economy is run on I always forget the
name of the [__] drug what's it
called again alessie captagon it's run
on that captagon drug oh you haven't
heard heard about this so Capon is like
this meth like club drug or something
and Assad
transferred basically the Syrian economy
into a captagon trafficking economy wow
that pushes it you know all over Europe
and stuff like that where it's used and
Joby when he was at the border of Syria
like last fall they were they were
watching all the trucks come across with
with with the Capon so what this guy I
talked to on the phone from Syria was
saying is he's like that's absolutely
correct the issue is that it's kind of a
self-fulfilling prophecy because the US
put so many sanctions on Syria as a
result of something allegedly very bad
you know with the with the chemical
weapons that it cut them off from so
much of the world that this is how they
have to stay afloat MH sure sanctions
are going to come back to bite us yeah
you know I think that American San
stions are what led to the creation of
bricks I was in I was can you expain
yeah um the bricks countries Brazil um
uh Russia India China South Africa and
then they've added a couple they've
added Iran and South Korea and a couple
of others um when I was
in China last year uh I was there for a
week for a conference and I was struck
by how few places took uh MasterCard and
Visa that doesn't surprise me well they
took this card called Panda card and
everybody had these panda cards so I
asked one of the shopkeepers what is
this Panda card and his explanation was
so like right on he said with visa and
MasterCard because they're American
companies all transactions are rooted
through New York right and so even if
the transaction Only Hits New York for a
tenth the second it's still considered
to be a us transaction so if the US
government imposes sanctions we can't
make that
transaction but what we did is we
created Panda card where all the
transactions go through Shanghai which
is their banking center and so if the
Americans put sanctions on us he said we
don't care we don't need visa and
MasterCard we have Panda card wow uhhuh
well now not only are the bricks
countries um merging their their
economies they're talking about a
unified um uh currency like the
Euro well if they have a EUR unified
currency American sanctions going to be
worthless and what do you think that is
a real threat to overtake the dollar I
do yeah last year for the very first
time China bought a shipment of oil from
Kuwait and paid for it in Yuan instead
of dollars never happened before
and we went back to the quades and we
raised all kinds of hell and they're
like look what are we going to do
they're a major Global power this is how
they wanted to pay for it yeah and it's
because we sanction everybody I remember
still being at the agency and and the
treasury Department had announced new
sanctions on Iran and I remember saying
to a colleague how many more sanctions
could there possibly be yeah like
haven't we sanctioned them in in every
facet of their economy self-fulfilling
prophecy man yeah that's exactly it I'm
not saying the intentions are always
evil or something like that it's just
people get it's the eye for an eye
people get carried away with it and it's
like you're going to make the problem
worse and we should see that now we're
going to talk about the Russia Ukraine
thing a little later I I I don't want to
jump to that because I I do want to keep
my promise and come back to to the
gabard thing because there's there's
there's an important Point here that I
keep thinking about in my head cuz I
like her too and I don't [__] know
her I hope she's cool but you know she's
qualified as you said she understands
how this world works all that's true and
let's say it's also true that she's a
great person has great
intentions she is still just like the
president by the way which should say
something about the problem with the
system she is still technically at the
mercy as a
dni or D is it DCI or dni dni dni right
she is still technically at the mercy of
the people who read her in on things
yeah she's not out there in the field
you're if they're in offices at these
different agencies and they're like
we're not telling this [__] this stuff
and I'll go one further than that oh
please um there are what 18 19 U
intelligence uh agencies in the US
government I forget what the the latest
the latest numbers that we know of
almost all of them are um are DOD
agencies right Army intelligence Air
Force Navy Marine Corps Dia DARPA NSA
they're
all components of the defense department
M so she doesn't have jurisdiction over
them Secretary of Defense she has no
jurisdiction zero the only thing she
controls is the budget she controls two
important things the the intelligence
Community budget and the president's
Daily Brief which was just in the last
couple of years transferred from the CIA
to the odni that's it but again it's
what they feed her in that too yeah
you're right you're right and it would
be easy to cut her out because then they
could say if called on it well the
secretary's briefed we report the
Secretary of Defense so he's briefed we
don't need to brief her now she has a
little bit more sway at the CIA but not
really I mean there was a listen in in
the Obama Administration there was this
huge fight because Obama announced that
he was going to start making NSA
officials and Dia officials station
Chiefs overseas okay and John Brennan
said I will resign if you do that that
would have been nice it would have been
nice would have been good for me yeah um
and Obama backed off so it's just CIA
officers that are station Chiefs
overseas most most places around the
world don't have anybody from NSA or Dia
or anywhere else it's just CIA but he
was trying to make it a truly
intelligence community position right
it's supposed to be but it's not never
has been um with Tuli that's going to be
her bureaucratic fight is remaining
relevant at the CIA because if you look
at the at the wiring diagram she's
technically above the CIA director but
in practice that's right it's more of a
dotted line and they're on the same line
yeah that's what I worry about because
it's like I I'm with you I worry about
it too it might not be her fault that
she ends up completely ineffective and
it's it's a waste you know and like
I that's another double-sided double
coin problem right here you point out
with the Brennan argument to Obama I
can't believe I'm going to steal man
John Brennon but like I understand why
he would want it to stay his people just
because I've heard all the stories from
you and everyone else and we can read
our history books about the inter agency
High School drama that happens God but
at the same time given the CIA all the
power to make these decisions and say
well we saw what we saw don't worry
about it right and these other agencies
then get rendered less effective at
their job too we used to laugh at these
other agencies we used to laugh that the
joke was the only reason that NSA and
Dia existed was as a pipeline for for
people uh to apply to the CIA or as
somewhere to go when you couldn't get
hired by the
CIA I just had a guy in here who
Matt hedger who did four years at NSA
and then they pulled him to be a knock
at
CIA I have deep respect for the Knox
that's hard work I do too that is hard
work he really he's different and he's
psychologically different too and he
explain like they look for different
things in that kind of job than they do
to hire you or L Deon right but he can
there were a lot of people are like oh
this is the fakest [__] ever bro he was
brought to me by Shaunie Delaney and
backed by Jim Lawler and he and he was
also I like Jim Lawler a lot Jim's a
Jim's a good guy Sol guy probably still
in the CIA but you know Julian I'm not
in the CIA I'm like the [__] you are Jim
but you know this guy the other thing we
I don't think we said this on the first
podcast with Matt because he has to come
back we got cut off he had a flight but
he got doxed on the dark web by a
foreign Intel service that's the only
reason he can talk cuz he was he was
known publicly they had to pull him out
like he's actually one guy who was like
yo I'm not still at CIA and I'm like
think I believe you you know I worked
for a former knock and he had been outed
by Al
James yeah yeah Ames outed a whole bunch
of people and they had to all be brought
in crazy because these guys that I I'm
glad there's someone that can do that I
couldn't do I couldn't do it oh my God
the things that he said he saw couldn't
do it I'm I'm told that that's what
amiris fox Kennedy did she was a knock
really yeah she was a uh an
international art consultant makes sense
uhhuh a lot of money in that a lot of
money a lot of hidden money in that a
lot of money laundering in that yes
that's what's fascinating about that
Leonardo one because I'm like all these
rich people they got their own little
world you know a a friend of mine who uh
works for the uh Treasury Department
told me that systems are pretty good
right now to the point where there are
only three ways to really launder money
and really get away with it he said Fine
Art real estate and race
horses that's it yeah makes sense we had
when I when I worked at Merill in in my
initial career on Wall Street you know
we work with these ultra high net worth
people right and it was funny
because there was one situation where
you know whenever we needed access to
anything we had people for that right
and we were like the quarterbacks and we
bring them in and there was one
situation I'll just say it involved cuz
you know it's privacy kind of things it
involved art and so
it was Big Art and I didn't know [__]
about [__] with this and so you know I'm
just following along this was my boss
running this one and I'm just kind of
watching and we brought in the main art
guy and I put two and two together later
I'm pretty sure it's the dude who was
the main expert in that lost Leonardo
documentary because he was the head of
Bank of America's trust department for
Fine Art and I couldn't remember the
guy's name cuz I never met with him but
like I remember those conversations with
my boss where I'm just asking him
questions not even about case we were
working on but like what people do with
this she's like dude wow even I like
look at this with like it has 10 heads
because people they you just declare a
value on something yeah yeah it's so
nobody knows you don't know it's worth
what somebody's willing to pay you for
it yeah and then you can it it you the
downstream effects of that on how you
Sosh around money I mean anyone out
there you don't have to like get in the
in the weeds with that it's exactly what
it looks like right so this lady was a
knock doing consulting for all like the
richest people and I wonder what that
she could find with that yeah she was
supposed to be the deputy CIA director
and um two weeks ago and Tom Cotton uh
that
that clown act from he's a statist yeah
he's a big time statist neocon from
Arkansas he said absolutely not why he
just doesn't like
her how why does he know her like that
he wanted to be the CIA director Tom
Cotton did yeah and he wanted to be CIA
director in Trump's first term and got
passed over for
Pompeo so um I think there's a little
bit of bitterness there and he's a young
guy he's only what in his early 40s
maybe yeah something like that and um
and here's this this upstart woman who
you know happens to be married to Bobby
Kennedy's son and she was the campaign
manager and why did she get to be the
deputy CIA director something should
have gone to me right so he um he sent
word to the White House that he would
filibuster her appointment and so the
president did something that was just so
smart he named her Deputy National
Security adviser which is a way more
important job because the CIA director
reports to the National Security adviser
right so now her title is Deputy
National Security
adviser I think for counter
no it's not for counterterrorism because
that's Seb Gorka who I have serious
problems
with would you care to elaborate oh my
God does anyone not have a problem with
that guy I have a personal problem and I
have a professional problem well I'm
your psychiatrist shoot John well the
professional problem is that he wears
his father's Nazi party lapel pin I've
seen that it's he's not a Neo-Nazi he's
an actual Nazi
from Nazi Hungary hard to deny that when
you're wearing that also
um the children of Hungarian
Nazis use the letter L as a middle
initial they they have two middle
initials they're given middle initial
and they put the letter
L and when he signs documents he adds
the
L which is [__] up that's crazy so are
you a Nazi or are you an American
right it bothers me very much we
shouldn't have in fact he he was only on
the National Security Council for 30
days in the in the first term because
the FBI is like the guy's a Nazi we
can't give him a security clearance and
you can't have us you can't have the job
of you know what was a deputy National
Security adviser or senior senior
director for
counterterrorism and not have a security
clearance so they got rid of him well
now he's back and and Trump has ordered
that the FBI give him his security
clearance okay number one number
two I was trying to get a pardon from
Trump in the first term and I hired a
republican lobbyist to help me she calls
me one day and she says Seb Gorka is
coming out with a book and there is a
party at the Trump Hotel and we're going
to have dinner at his house afterwards
so she
says I want you to come and I said but
why why would I ask Sebastian Gorka to
help me yeah like what what reach does
he have and she said he's the only
non-trump family member that Trump
follows on Twitter at time yeah you told
me keep going you told me the story good
so I said okay she says we want him to
tweet at the president pardon John
kiraku and then she says bring your
checkbook and I said oh it's going to be
one of those nights and she said yeah
he's going to ask you for
$2,000 and I said all right I said I
I've been in Washington long enough I'll
that yeah I know how the game is played
I'll give him to ,000 to tweet cheap
date so I go to Trump and
um and he's you know handing out his
book whatever it was I don't even
remember and everybody like every
elected Republican in Washington is
there it was kind of a big deal and
so she takes me up to him she says she
says Seb this is John kyaku I told you
about him and he says with that British
accent I want to smack right out of his
face so you're the chap who wants me to
tweet and I said if you're so inclined
and he says well you're coming to dinner
tonight and I said yes we'll see at your
house we'll go to the house
afterwards and uh he pulls me aside and
he says so you want me to tweet what
pardon John kyaku and I said yes and he
says give me
$5,000 I said
$5,000 for a tweet and he said yeah give
me
$5,000 I said you know I've been in
Washington for 40 years and I'm not a
babe in the woods I know how it's played
but I'm not going to be shaken down by
you or by anybody else and I walked out
good for you I like those stories I
don't have any respect for the guy at
all and I honestly I have no idea what
Trump sees in him I I also like when I
hear stuff like that it get it so
confuses me because the guy wears the
Nazi lapel type pin you're telling me he
signs his name with like I'm I'm unaware
of that symbolism but I believe you and
he loves Trump who's like buddies with
Israel yeah very confusing we've never
in our history had a more pro-israel
president and then just a couple of
weeks ago maybe it was more than a
couple maybe it was a month ago just
before the inauguration he made this big
announcement that I am a Zionist he said
it's accepted yeah but you're wearing a
Nazi party lapel pin people are confused
these days John they don't know what a
gender is anymore well that's true too
he's he's he's political fluid yeah
that's right there will be a lot of that
yeah there's going to be a lot of that
but the the thing that we're looking at
with some of these people that Trump's
putting in is like the the transparency
angle which we're laying out some of the
issues that could happen there with
someone like gabard but then there's
also these pop culture and also National
Security related type things that people
are concerned about there's two things I
want to hit on here because I am cynical
about both of them and if you can
correct that I would love that first one
is the J k thing yeah so they're saying
Trump so far is keeping his promise on
that and he's saying he's ordering the
release yes he said last time and I've
seen Pompeo talked about this he said
Mike Pompeo is the one who stopped it
because like names and addresses or
something like that but I actually
cynically unfortunately agree with the
people like Andy boo Deonte who say even
if they were involved those documents
would have been destroyed right after it
happened or never created and so we're
not really going to find out most likely
is that what that's what you think I
think I think Andy's correct um we're
talking about well let's let's back up
Congress passed a law in
1992 mandating the release of documents
having to do with the JFK assassination
the RFK assassination and the Martin
Luther King assassination
1992 and every year the CIA Whispers in
the president's ear and says sources and
methods Security National Security
911 you can't release it and president
after president after president
um blocks the
release so many of us were very hopeful
in Trump's first term that it would
finally come
out now it's going to come out he's
serious this time he made the final
decision it's coming out and I think
it's like they have 30 days to release
the JFK and 60 days for the RFK and the
MLK
um I was talking to a guy at the
National Security archive which is at
George Washington University and they're
the ones that usually take um custody of
these Declassified documents it it's a
hub for people working on phds or for
journalists working on um stories where
they need access to original CIA
documents sure so I said to him the
other day tell me if I'm wrong but I'm
going to make an educated guess and I'm
going to guess that these documents are
going to be either documents that have
already been released but were more
heavily redacted in the past they're
going to be less redacted this time and
they're probably going to be about CIA
surveillance activities in Mexico City
in October and November of
1963 and he said I think that's exactly
what it's going to be it's not going to
be a Smoking Gun it's not going to tell
tell us who killed Kennedy it may be
moderately interesting to a handful of
phds who have followed this stuff for
years but we're not going to learn
anything new from these documents I'm a
little bit more hopeful about RFK and
MLK why well because there are more
clear-cut questions that have never been
answered in those killings um RFK to me
is the is the most interesting and I
don't mean to sound like a you know tin
tin foil hat person I'm not you you know
on your head yeah you know me I'm I'm a
straight shooter but
um sirun sir was was convicted of of
killing Bobby Kennedy in the kitchen of
the Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles he
did have a great name I have to give him
that s s yeah it's a good name I'm
ashamed that he's Greek Orthodox yeah
it's a great name it's long been a
source of pain for many of us in the
Greek Orthodox I know so
um he had a revolver that that held
seven uh rounds and eight bullets were
recovered and in addition to that a
forensic investigation
an auditory investigation conducted in
1993 found that there were between 10
and 13 shots that were fired Thomas
naguchi who was the um coroner the Los
Angeles County Coroner at the time and
famous famous nationally yes um
determined that the kill shot came at
the back of the head at the top of the
neck um from a distance of 1 to three
inches but Sirhan was in front of
Kennedy so how did the kill shot come
from behind Magic Bullet Magic Bullet
just like JFK yeah at the same time
there was a security guard by the name
of uh Cesar who was a uh white
supremacist his name was Cesar I know
and he was a white supremacist pretty
dog on ironic confusing yeah so he hated
Bobby Kennedy and he told a reporter
afterwards that the reason he hated
Kennedy was that if elected that Kennedy
was going to bring all of the and the
into government like his brother did
sorry no no you're good I we got to mark
that um there was a video that the
National Geographic Channel uh found in
the 90s where you see Cesar in the very
back of the kitchen and he reaches into
his waistband and he pulls out a gun and
then you hear bang bang bang bang bang
bang bang and he puts the gun back in
his belt so the reporter asked him did
you did you shoot Robbie uh Bobby
Kennedy and he said no I was going to
mhm so that one too sorry oh yeah yeah
you're good sorry I got to do that you
it's yeah YouTube It's brutal so
um how many shooters were
there uh that's one question how many
shooters were there and who were they so
he ended up being polygraphed by the
FBI and he passed the polygraph he did
not shoot Kennedy he wanted to he
intended to but he didn't which isn't a
crime MH that's right that was number
one number two
was Siran Siran has been utterly
inconsistent about that night when first
arrested he said he did it he was proud
that he did it and that he did it with
20 years of malice of forethought his
words because of Kennedy's support for
Israel and he's
Palestinian then he said but he's Greek
Orthodox yeah a lot of Palestinians are
Christians and most of them are Greek
Orthodox some are Catholic right yeah so
he later said I didn't do it and then
still later he said I may have done it I
just don't remember and then later yet
he said I suppose I could have done it
but I don't have any memory of it well
we also learned 20 years after the fact
fact that he may have participated when
he was in college in um a medical
experiment that turned out to be a
component of MK
Ultra and so we don't really know the
answers to these
questions I'm
hopeful that there will be some answers
now the FBI said two weeks ago oh my
goodness we just found another 1,800
pages of documents related to the RFK
assassination that we didn't know
existed they were in this guy's desk
since
1968 seriously can you imagine working
in a place like
that the CIA at least will admit well we
destroyed all the
doents the old school way yeah the old
school way that's what we did in the old
days yeah like when they told Gina
haspel don't destroy the torture tapes
and she goes back and puts them in a
grind
yeah so maybe we get more on RFK I hope
so and then what about MLK because
that's FBI that's FBI I know they're
your favorite agency yeah and and RFK is
FBI as well for the most part except MK
Ultra yeah yeah I heard MK Ultra I'm not
thinking FBI would you say that MK uh
FBI Visa V two or more Shooters okay MLK
is fascinating to me
um I always believed that James RL Reay
killed Martin Luther King and then I
decided if if I'm going to have an
opinion it needs to be an educated
opinion so I'm going to read everything
I can get my hands on about Martin
Luther King's killing
and I think that if James R Reay killed
him he was to use Lee Harvey Oswald's
word he was a py yeah cuz look at it
this
way here's a guy who was drunk all the
time time all the time he just had a
well documented lifelong drinking
problem and he decided he's going to
kill Martin Luther King and so he goes
to a boarding house that is a full block
away from the hotel where Martin Luther
King was the Lorraine Motel where Martin
Luther King was
staying this boarding house was a
Rundown Flea bag place the rooms didn't
have bathrooms there was one bathroom at
the end of the hall and the bathroom at
the end of the hall had a window in the
shower one of these long narrow windows
that had a view of the
Lorraine so we're supposed to believe
that this drunk guy with a 40-year-old
rifle sat in a public
bathroom all day long nobody ever
noticed him
and then he hits the perfect shot from a
block
away come on seriously now couple that
with what we know for 100% fact that the
FBI tried to get Martin Luther King to
commit suicide two years earlier they
sent him a a letter an anonymous letter
that purported to be from uh an
anti-king African-American man saying
you're a disgrace to the black people
you should do the only honorable thing
you know and by all accounts he laughed
he was like J that was never going to
work yeah like come on we know that we
have people who say that about us I know
right you know how many death threats
I've gotten oh my god um but uh they
said we're going to tell your wife that
you cheat on her it's like go ahead
knows I cheat
on common knowledge my friend yeah so he
just dismissed it but the hatred of King
at the FBI was was enough in the' 60s
that make people
think perhaps they did it perhaps they
set him up perhaps they worked with with
James Earl Reay we don't know and we
don't really have any idea what these
documents might be and why they've been
classified if this is a if this is a
criminal act nothing should be
classified yeah right he didn't have you
know an elected office he didn't have a
security clearance he didn't have access
to classified information he's just you
know he he's a a preacher and a civil
rights leader so why would that case be
classified in the first place so I'm
kind of excited about what that release
is going to be and you think we could
really get something there I think
there's a chance that some of these big
questions might get answered and you
don't think James R re could have
floated around in a bathroom for a lot
of hours you did believe like an hour
ago that maybe someone had fished the
[__] of Abraham Lincoln out of a toilet
after he got shot so you know it was
thinking I admit it it was wishful
thinking you know I remember I was a
little kid and James R Reay escaped from
prison and I remember watching the news
with my folks and being shocked at the
people being interviewed who were saying
well I hope he comes to my house cuz
I'll hide him I'll hide him he's a hero
oh my God and my parents just being like
appalled that people in America that's
wild yeah it's crazy that's I think I
must have been like eight or nine years
old still like you would think at that
point people would move on with life
yeah move on seriously crazy wow what
about the other one though you know what
one I'm going to ask about which one the
files the ones that were just magically
shut from everyone at the end of 2021 at
the end of Gan Max trial oh that you
know I almost forgot about that talk
about literally no reason to be
classified thank you guys for watching
the episode before you leave please be
sure to hit that subscribe button and
smash that like button on the video it's
a huge help and also if you're over on
Instagram be sure to follow the show at
Julian Dory podcast or also on my
personal page at Julian D Dory both
links are in the description below
finally if you'd like to catch up on our
latest episodes use the Julian Dory
podcast playlist Link in the description
below thank you